http://www.o-generator.com/o-generator-help/

NEW IPAD APP
FREE SCHOOL TRIAL
What is O-Generator?
Support & FAQ’s
What is O-Generator?
Instant answers to common questions
O-Generator iPad AppIf you are looking for further help working with the O-Generator iPad App please select from the following.
How does the O-Generator iPad version work?
Composition Ideas on the iPad
Where do I log-in to use O-GeneratorSCHOOLS
Your school may have its own page at yourschool.musicfirst.co.uk – Check with your teacher or school administrator.
SINGLE USER LICENCE
Go to www.musicfirst.com
I've lost a password to log-inTEACHER – Contact your school administrator or if O-Music are your administrator contact us using the form below.
STUDENT – Contact your class teacher or school administrator. O-Music cannot give passwords to students.
Your Name (required)
Your Email (required)
Your School
Your Phone Number
Your Message
Some menus are not showing or notes are not playingYou may need to clear your browser cache. Please follow the Google Chrome guidelines.
My tunes are not playing in timeLike most music software, O-Generator requires a certain level of performance from your PC or Tablet.
We recommend that your PC has at least an Intel Core i3 processor.
Disabling other software will also improve performance.
What browser must I have to use O-Generator - December 2014Music software on-line uses the latest HTML5 standards. We recommend using Google Chrome 35+
How do I install Google Chrome on our school network?Roger Dixon has produced this excellent guide for installing Chrome on school networks.
Privacy and Data Protection Policy
O-Music Privacy and Data Protection Policy
O-Music Ltd is fully compliant with the GDPR law for the UK/EU from 25th May 2018
Administrator(s)
We keep securely the name and email address of the person or persons allocated by the school as the administrator(s) of the software for the school.
We supply a temporary password and username, which the administrator can then alter. All passwords are encrypted and as soon as the administrator changes it, only the administrator knows what it is.
It is the responsibility of the administrator to ensure no student or any other unauthorised person has access to these logon credentials.
The administrator can add the names, usernames and classes of students to the system. He/she can also add teacher details: names, usernames, email addresses and encrypted passwords.
The administrator can also attach teachers to classes so that the teacher can see a list of students in that class, with names and usernames. Passwords are hidden.
The administrator can also in certain circumstances ask O-Music Ltd  to undertake some of these tasks, in which case the operation will be carried out by a member of O-Music staff trained in data protection.
Teachers
Teachers have access to the names and usernames of the students in the classes to which they have been attached by the administrator. They can change their own details and those of the students in those classes. They do not have access to any secret student passwords but may change them, for instance if a student has forgotten theirs.
Students
Each student has access to his/her name and username. The password is hidden but may be changed by the administrator. Students have no access to anybody else’s details unless they become aware of another person’s username and password.
Deletion
The administrator can immediately delete any student, teacher or groups of students from the list, or delete all students and all teachers.
The administrator may in an emergency ask O-Music Ltd to suspend the software. This will be done by changing the access URL (web address) to a new secret version. This will have the effect of stopping any user making use of the software.
Servers
O-Music uses two servers:
•Server 1 used by the parent company MusicFirst, stores user details as described above. It is located in the UK.  Music First Privacy Policy.
•Server 2 in the US stores the O-Generator software, media and test results.
Data Processing in the European Economic Area (EEA)
A MusicFirst “Data Region” is a set of data centres located within a defined geographical area where User data is stored. Personal data is not transmitted between Data Regions. For Users with accounts located in MusicFirst’s European Data Region, all processing of personal data is performed in accordance with privacy rights and regulations following the EU Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 (the “Directive”), and the implementation of the Directive in local legislation. From May 25, 2018, the Directive and local legislation based on the Directive will be replaced by the Regulations (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, known as the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), and MusicFirst’s processing will take place in accordance with GDPR.
MusicFirst processes personal data as both a Processor and Controller, as defined in the Directive and the GDPR. Consequently, MusicFirst processes all data provided by its Users with accounts in its European Data Region, in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) only.
What are your choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information?
The disclosure of very limited personal information is required to create an account on our site, which is required to access certain services. If you do not wish to disclose the requisite information you are free to discontinue use of the MusicFirst website and service.
You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies MusicFirst may not be displayed or function in the way intended by MusicFirst.
Right of confirmation – Users and Visitors will have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from MusicFirst the confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him or her his being processed. If a data subject wishes to avail him or herself of this right of confirmation, he or she may, at any time, contact our Data Protection Officer.
Right of access – Users and Visitors will have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from MusicFirst free information about his or her personal data stored at any time and a copy of this information. Furthermore, the European directives and regulations grant the data subject access to the following information: (1) the purpose of the processing; (2) the categories of personal data concerned; (3) the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data has been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations; (4) where possible, the anticipated period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period; (5) the existence of the right to request from MusicFirst rectification or erasure of personal data, or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the data subject, or to object to such processing; (6) the existence of the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority; (7) where the personal data is not collected from the data subject, any available information as to its source; (8) the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling, referred to in Article 22(1) and (4) of the GDPR and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and anticipated consequences of such processing for the data subject.
Furthermore, the data subject shall have a right to obtain information as to whether personal data is transferred to a third country or to an international organisation. Where this is the case, the data subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards relating to the transfer.
If a data subject wishes to avail him or herself of this right of access, he or she may at an time contact our Data Protection Officer.
Right of rectification – Each User or Visitor shall have the right to obtain from MusicFirst without undue delay, the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him or her; and to complete incomplete data.
Right of restriction of processing – Each User or Visitor shall have the right to obtain from MusicFirst restriction of processing where: (1) the accuracy of the personal data is contested; (2) processing is unlawful and the data subject requests restriction rather than erasure; (3) MusicFirst no longer needs the personal data for the purpose of the processing; or (4) the data subject has objected to processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of MusicFirst override those of the data subject.
Right to withdraw consent – Each Visitor and User shall have the right to withdraw his or her consent to processing of his or her personal data at any time by contacting our Data Protection Officer.
Contacts
O-Music Ltd will keep securely names, addresses and email addresses of teachers who ask for trial versions or otherwise ask for more information. This information will be used in the following ways:
•To tell trial users their logon credentials and to remind them.
•To send further details including prices
•To warn users of the ending of trials
Administrators will also be contacted from time to time with newsletters and information about the expiry of their subscription.
All contacts will have the right to have their details deleted from the database.
Privacy impact assessment
O-Music Ltd has a number of strategies in place to secure data, with strict limits on the number of people who have access. Only the administrators have access to the full data, i.e. the list of students the administrator has assigned to O-Music Ltd. Class teachers only have access to data for individual classes to which they have been assigned. All data is protected by secret usernames and passwords. Passwords are hidden and encrypted.
In the extremely unlikely event of data being stolen, the impact will be limited to student names, usernames and classes. No student email addresses, phone numbers, gender information, age, date of birth or address are stored.
The only other data stored consists of the teacher’s names, school email addresses and school address.
Terms of useO-MUSIC END-USER LICENSE AGREEMENT
This Agreement licenses the use of software to you and contains warranty and liability disclaimers.
1. DEFINITIONS
(a) “O-MUSIC Software” means the software program covered by this Agreement, and all related updates supplied by O-MUSIC.
(b) “O-GENERATOR” means the O-MUSIC Software and any related documentation, models and multimedia content (such as animation, sound and graphics), and all related updates supplied by O-MUSIC.
(c) “End-User Product” means the output file generated by you, if any, using the O-MUSIC Software. Examples of End-User Products include animations, presentations, interactive multimedia material, interactive entertainment products, compositions and the like.
(d) “compositions” means using a sound repeated or many sounds repeated over a period of time.
2. LICENSE
The O-Generator License Agreement allows you to:
(a) Use the O-GENERATOR Product on the agreed amount of computers as defined on your purchase invoice.
(b) Make copies of the End-User Product and distribute those copies for use by others.
3. RESTRICTIONS
You may not make or distribute copies of the O-GENERATOR Product, or electronically transfer the O-GENERATOR Product from one computer to another or over a network other than the agreed amount on your sales invoice. You may not decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or otherwise reduce the O-MUSIC Software to a human-perceivable form. You may not modify, rent, resell for profit, distribute or create derivative works based upon the O-GENERATOR Product or any part thereof.
4. OWNERSHIP
The foregoing license gives you limited rights to use the O-GENERATOR Product. You do not become the owner of, and O-MUSIC retains title to, the O-GENERATOR Product, and all copies thereof. All rights not specifically granted in this Agreement, including International Copyrights, are reserved by O-MUSIC.
5. LIMITATION OF DAMAGES:
O-MUSIC SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR LOSS (INCLUDING DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF BUSINESS, LOSS OF PROFITS, OR THE LIKE), WHETHER BASED ON BREACH OF CONTRACT, TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE), PRODUCT LIABILITY OR OTHERWISE, EVEN IF O-MUSIC OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. The limited warranty, exclusive remedies and limited liability set forth above are fundamental elements of the basis of the bargain between O-MUSIC and you. You agree that O-MUSIC would not be able to provide the O-MUSIC Software on an economic basis without such limitations.
6. USE OF SOUNDS
You may modify, publish and distribute the included sounds provided you are not marketing or distributing your work as sounds. You may create and distribute your own compositions.
© O-MUSIC 1998-2018
O-MUSIC LIMITED
View TOP LESSON IDEAS
